Eugene Otto Weber Murman Watercolors of California Flora, 1941-1961
Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library History and Special Collections Division
- Orchidaceae (Orchid) Family. 1941-1942, Series 59.; 6 entries
  - Calypso bulbosa (calypso). (Box 11, Folder 215)
    no collection date; Marin to Siskiyou and Del Norte Counties, north to Alaska; bogs or in leaf-mold or pine forests (fr. Jepson)
  - Corallorrhiza striata (striped coral root). (Box 11, Folder 216)
    no collection date; woods along coast from Santa Cruz to Humboldt Counties; Sierra Nevada from Fresno to Modoc to Siskiyou Counties; north to British Columbia (fr. Jepson)
  - Cypripedium californicum (lady'slipper).6/13/41 (Box 11, Folder 217)
    Patrick Creek Lodge, Del Norte County
  - Cypripedium montanum (mountain lady's slipper).6/9/42 (Box 11, Folder 218)
    Siskiyou County at Oregon line
  - Epipactis gigantea (stream orchis).6/13/41 (Box 11, Folder 219)
  - Habenaria sparsiflora (rein-orchis).6/15/41 (Box 11, Folder 220)
    Hwy #199 near Hiiochi Bridge, Del Norte County
- Orobanchaceae (Broom-rape) Family. 1951, Series 60.; 1 entry
  - Orobanche comosa var. violacea (purple broom-rape).8/2/51 (Box 12, Folder 221)
    Pigeon Point, San Mateo County
- Papaveraceae (Poppy) Family. 1943-1955, Series 61.; 5 entries
  - Argemone platyceras (prickly-poppy; chicalote).6/3/52 (Box 12, Folder 222)
    Angeles Crest, Los Angeles County, 5,000' elevation
  - Dendromecon rigida (bush poppy).2/18/55, 6/11/55 (Box 24, Folder 479)
  - Dicentra chrysantha (golden ear-drops).5/11/57 (Box 21, Folder 417)
    Santa Barbara Botanic Garden; plate indicates Family: Fumariaceae
  - Dicentra formosa (bleeding heart).6/13/57 (Box 21, Folder 416)
  - Romneya coulteri (matilija poppy).6/21/43 (Box 12, Folder 223)
- Pinaceae (Pine) Family. 1941-1961, Series 62.; 38 entries
  one entry has been moved to Family: Cupressaceae, according to IPNI classification
  - Abies amabilis (cascade fir; lovely fir).9/12/53 (Box 12, Folder 224)
    also slide #192; Cascade Mountains, OR; found in Siskiyou Mountains, CA, by James Roof of Tilden Park Botanic Garden
  - Abies amabilis (cascade fir; lovely fir)., map (Box 12, Folder 224a)
    no colledtion date; map from W. Metcalf, showing only know location
  - Abies concolor (white fir).9/18/41 (Box 12, Folder 225)
    also slide #193; Shasta National Forest
  - Abies grandis (lowland fir). (Box 12, Folder 226)
    also slide #194; no other data
  - Abies magnifica (red fir).9/17/41 (Box 12, Folder 227)
    also slide #195; Stanislaus National Forest
  - Abies magnifica var. shastensis (Shasta red fir). (Box 12, Folder 228)
    also slide #196; no other data
  - Abies procera (noble fir).9/1/60 (Box 23, Folder 446)
    Siskiyou Mountains; Mount Hood, OR
  - Abies procera (noble fir).6/18/61, 7/5/61 (Box 26, Folder 516)
    Siskiyou Mountains, 3,000'-5,000' elevation; Oregon coast range and Marys Peak, OR
  - Abies venusta (Santa Lucia fir).9/2/42 (Box 12, Folder 229)
    also slide #197; Miller Canyon, Monterey County
  - Picea breweriana (Brewer's spruce; weeping spruce).12/12/41 (Box 12, Folder 231)
    also slide #199; Happy Camp, Klamath National Forest, Siskiyou County
  - Picea engelmannii (Engelmann spruce).10/2042 (Box 12, Folder 232)
    also slide #200; Sugar Pine Creek on Russian Mountain, Siskiyou County Sections 29-32, T 40 N, R 9 W; Clarks Creek, Shasta County, Sections 21 & 28
  - Picea sitchensis (tideland spruce). (Box 12, Folder 233)
    Mendocino County north to Del Norte County, north to Alaska; lowlands facing the ocean (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus albicaulis (white-bark pine).9/18/41 (Box 12, Folder 234)
    also slide #202; Trinity National Forest, Yalla Bolly Mountains
  - Pinus aristata (bristle-cone pine; hickory pine).9/15/41 (Box 12, Folder 235)
    also slide #223; White Mountains, Inyo County, 11,000' elevation
  - Pinus aristata (bristle-cone pine; hickory pine).6/24/60 (Box 23, Folder 445)
    White Mountains, Inyo County, 10,200' elevation
  - Pinus balfouriana (foxtail pine).9/18/41 (Box 12, Folder 236)
    also slide #203; Trinity National Forest, Yolla Bolla Mountains
  - Pinus cembroides var. monophylla (one-leaf pinon). (Box 12, Folder 237)
    also slide #204; no collection date; local on west slope, Sierra Nevada from Tuolumne to Kern Rivers; common on desert slopes and ranges (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus cembroides var. parryana (Parry pinon).8/18/41 (Box 12, Folder 238)
    also slide #205; Elysian Park, Los Angeles County
  - Pinus contorta (beach pine).6/10/41 (Box 12, Folder 239)
    also slide #206; Trinidad, Humboldt County
  - Pinus contorta var. murrayana (tamarac pine). (Box 12, Folder 240)
    no collection date; Sierra Nevada; San Bernardino and San Jacinto Mountains; dry slopes or swampy swales, 6,000'-10,000' (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus coulteri (big cone pine). (Box 13, Folder 241)
    also slide #208; no collection date; Mt. Diablo (12,000' elevation), Mt. Hamilton, San Carlos and Santa Lucia Ranges; dry, rocky mountain slopes, 3,000'-6,500' elevation (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus flexilis (limber pine).8/28/41 (Box 13, Folder 242)
    Tahquitz Peak, Riverside County
  - Pinus flexilis (limber pine).2/16/42 (Box 13, Folder 243)
    also slide #209; head of Rock Creek, Mono County, 11,300' elevation
  - Pinus lambertiana (sugar pine). (Box 13, Folder 244)
    also slide #210; no collection date; Sierra Nevada in main timber belt; higher coast ranges, So. CA to OR; montane, 2,500'-7,000' (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus monticola (silver pine). (Box 13, Folder 245)
    also slide #211; no collection date; Sierra Nevada in main timber belt, 6,000'-9,500'; Mt. Shasta to Marble Mountain and Siskiyou Mountains, north to British Columbia (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus muricata (Bishop pine).4/19/41 (Box 13, Folder 246)
    also slide #212; Rancho Santa Ana, Orange County
  - Pinus ponderosa (yellow pine). (Box 13, Folder 247)
    also slide #213; no collection date; most abundant species in Sierra Nevada, main timber belt; higher coast ranges; high mountains of So. CA (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus ponderosa var. jeffreyi (Jeffrey pine). (Box 13, Folder 248)
    also slide #214; no collection date; Sierra Nevada; Mt. San Jacinto and San Bernardino Mountains; Yollo to Siskiyou Mountains; high montane, 6,000'-7,000' elevation (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus radiata (Monterey pine). (Box 13, Folder 249)
    also slide #215; no collection date; Ano Nuevo Pt., Santa Cruz County; Monterey; Cambria, San Luis Obispo; seacoast only in a few, small, scattered communities (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus remorata (island pine).2/18/55 (Box 24, Folder 480)
    Santa Cruz Island
  - Pinus sabiniana (digger pine). (Box 13, Folder 250)
    also slide #216; no collection date; Sierra foothills; coast ranges mostly toward the interior and foothils, forming a very thin stand (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus torreyana (Torrey pine). (Box 13, Folder 251)
    also slide #217; no collection date; local to San Diego coast about Del Mar; Soledad Canyon; Santa Rosa Island (fr. Jepson)
  - Pinus tuberculata (knob cone pine). (Box 13, Folder 252)
    also slide #218; no collection date; Santa Lucia and Santa Cruz Mountains; Moraga Ridge; Mt. St. Helena north; barren or rocky slopes at median elevations (fr. Jepson)
  - Pseudotsuga macrocarpa (big cone spruce). (Box 13, Folder 253)
    also slide #219; no collection date; San Emicdino Mountains, west to San Rafael and Santa Inez ranges; canyons and north slopes, 2,500'-8,000' (fr. Jepson)
  - Pseudotsuga macrocarpa (big cone spruce).3/18/60 (Box 23, Folder 444)
    Arroyo Seco, Pasadena, Los Angeles County
  - Pseudotsuga taxifolia (Douglas fir; Douglas spruce).10/20/42 (Box 13, Folder 254)
    also slide #220; outskirts of Portland, OR
  - Tsuga heterophylla (coast hemlock).9/25/42 (Box 13, Folder 255)
    also slide #221; Wind River Valley, Columbia National Forest, OR
  - Tsuga mertensiana (mountain hemlock).9/25/42 (Box 13, Folder 256)
    also slide #222; type specimen from 4,000', Reed Mountain, Columbia National Park, OR
- Platanaceae (Plane-tree) Family. 1955, Series 63.; 1 entry
  - Platanus racemosa (western sycamore).2/18/55, 3/19/55 (Box 24, Folder 461)
- Plumbaginaceae (Leadwort [Thrift]) Family. 1951, Series 64.; 1 entry
  - Statice arctica var. californica (sea-pink; thrift).8/24/51 (Box 13, Folder 257)
- Polemoniaceae (Phlox) Family. 1942-1961, Series 65.; 4 entries
  - Gilia achilleaefolia (blue gilia).7/7/60 (Box 23, Folder 456)
    Woodland Hills, Los Angeles County; plate indicates English family name: Gilia Family
  - Gilia aggregata (scarlet gilia; sky rocket).7/17/55 (Box 24, Folder 462)
    Mammoth, Mono County, 8,000' elevation
  - Gilia californica (prickly phlox).5/24/42 (Box 13, Folder 258)
    also slide #224; Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County; plate indicates English family name: Gilia Family
  - Gilia latifolia (broad-leaved gilia).4/22/61 (Box 26, Folder 503)
- Polygonaceae (Buckwheat) Family. 1941-1957, Series 66.; 8 entries
  - Eriogonum arborescens (Santa Cruz Island buckwheat).5/11/57 (Box 22, Folder 438)
    Santa Cruz Island; also collected Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
  - Eriogonum crocatum (saffron eriogonum).7/2/57 (Box 22, Folder 439)
    Conejo Grade, Ventura County
  - Eriogonum elatum (no common name).6/13/41 (Box 13, Folder 259)
    Patrick Creek, Del Norte County, Hwy. #199
  - Eriogonum fasciculatum (California buckwheat; flat-top).9/30/51 (Box 13, Folder 260)
    also slide #225; Vedugo Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Eriogonum giganteum (Saint Catherine's lace).7/12/57 (Box 22, Folder 437)
    Santa Catalina and San Clemente Islands; also collected at Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden
  - Eriogonum latifolium (coast eriogonum; tibinagua).8/24/51 (Box 14, Folder 261)
    coast, San Mateo County
  - Eriogonum parvifolium (dune eriogonum).8/22//51 (Box 14, Folder 262)
    dunes of Monterey coast
  - Eriogonum umbellatum (sulphur flower).8/23/52 (Box 14, Folder 263)
    Mammoth, Mono County, 8,500' elevation
- Primulaceae (Primrose) Family., Series 67.; 1 entry
  - Dodecatheon hendersonii (mosquito bills; sailor caps). (Box 14, Folder 264)
    coast ranges from Monterey to Siskiyou Counties; south in Sierra Nevada foothills to Tulare County; February to April (fr. Jepson)
- Ranunculaceae (Buttercup) Family. 1941-1959, Series 68.; 6 entries
  - Aconitum columbianum (western monkshood).8/19/52 (Box 14, Folder 265)
  - Aquilegia truncata (columbine).6/3/41 (Box 14, Folder 266)
    Mt. Saint Helena, Napa County
  - Clematis lasiantha (virgin's bower; pipe stem).2/25/59; 4/29/59 (Box 17, Folder 324)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden; plate indicates English family name: Crowfoot Family
  - Delpinium cardinale (scarlet larkspur).7/3/41 (Box 14, Folder 267)
  - Delphinium parryi (Parry's larkspur).5/14/43 (Box 14, Folder 268)
  - Paeonia brownii (western peony).2/25/56 (Box 20, Folder 390)
    Big Tujunga Canyon, Los Angeles County; plate indicates English family name: Crowfoot Family
- Rhamnaceae (Buckthorn) Family. 1952-1957, Series 69.; 9 entries
  - Ceanothus arboreus (island lilac).3/8/54 (Box 14, Folder 269)
    Vedugo Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Ceanothus crassifolius (hoary-leaf ceanothus).2/23/52 (Box 14, Folder 270)
    also slide #226; Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County; also colleced in May & August
  - Ceanothus cynaeus (San Diego ceanothus).2/18/55 (Box 21, Folder 415)
  - Ceanothus impressus (Santa Barbara ceanothus).4/3/54; 6/13/57 (Box 22, Folder 422)
  - Ceanothus papillosus var. roweanus (wart-leaf ceanothus).2/7/53 (Box 14, Folder 271)
    Mt. Tranquillon, Santa Barbara County
  - Ceanothus thyrsiflorus var. griseus (no common name).3/26/55 (Box 21, Folder 402)
  - Rhamnus californica (coffee berry; pidgeon berry; yerba del oso).9/15/57, 6/57 (Box 22, Folder 421)
    Verdugo Hills, Glendale, Los Angeles County
  - Rhamnus crocea var. ilicifolia (holly-leaf coffee; red berry).2/1/53, 7/1/52 (Box 14, Folder 272)
    also slide #227; Chatsworth Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Rhamnus purshiana (cascara sagrada).6/10/55, 8/1/55 (Box 21, Folder 403)
    Klamath, Del Norte County
- Rosaceae (Rose) Family. 1952-1959, Series 70.; 18 entries
  - Adenostoma fasciculatum (greasewood; chamise).5/4/52 (Box 14, Folder 273)
  - Adenostoma sparsifoium (ribbon wood; yerba del pasmo).7/10/58 (Box 19, Folder 367)
  - Cercocarpus betuloides (mountain mahogany; hardtack ).2/7/53, 6/53 (Box 14, Folder 274)
    also slide #228; Santa Barbara County
  - Chamaebatiaria millefolium (fern bush; desert sweet).6/13/57 (Box 22, Folder 426)
  - Cowania stansburiana (rock rose).4/3/54 (Box 14, Folder 275)
    eastern Mojave Desert
  - Crataegus douglasii (black hawthorn).5/20/58, 7/19/58 (Box 19, Folder 368)
  - Fallugia paradoxa (Apache plume).6/1/53 (Box 14, Folder 276)
    Providence Mountains, San Bernardino County
  - Holodiscus discolor (creambush).6/20/58 (Box 19, Folder 369)
  - Lyonothamnus asplenifolius (Catalina Island ironwood), part a.11/24/53 (Box 14, Folder 277)
    Catalina Island; part b of plate illustrates L. floribundus
  - Osmaronia cerasiformis (oso berry).3/14/58, 6/3/58 (Box 18, Folder 351)
  - Photinia arbutifolia (toyon; California holly).7/13/53, 11/2/53 (Box 14, Folder 278)
    also slide #229; Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Physocarpus capitatus (ninebark).5/20/58 (Box 19, Folder 370)
  - Prunus eriogyna (desert apricot).1/20/59 (Box 17, Folder 338)
    Hwy. #78, between Banner and Scissors Crossing
  - Prunus ilicifolia (islay; holly-leaf cherry).2/7/54, 8/30/54 (Box 14, Folder 279)
  - Prunus lyonii (Catalina cherry).5/11/57, 9/57 (Box 22, Folder 427)
    Catalina, San Clemente and Santa Cruz Islands; Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
  - Purshia tridentata (antelope brush).6/18/58 (Box 19, Folder 371)
    McBride Spring, Shasta County, 5,000' elevation
  - Sorbus sitchensis (western mountain ash).10/24/55 (Box 21, Folder 404)
    Castle Lake, Siskiyou County, 5,600' elevation
  - Spiraea menziesii (Menzies' spiraea).6/13/57 (Box 22, Folder 428)
- Rubiaceae (Madder) Family. 1957, Series 71.; 1 entry
  - Cephalanthus occidentalis (button bush).7/12/57 (Box 21, Folder 418)
- Rutaceae (Rue) Family. 1957-1958, Series 72.; 3 entries
  - Cneoridium dumosum (berry rue; bush rue).1/6/58 (Box 18, Folder 349)
  - Ptelea baldwinii (western hop-tree).4/15/58, 8/2/58 (Box 18, Folder 350)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden; Mt. Diablo, Contra Costa County
  - Thamnosma montana (turpentine broom).5/31/57 (Box 22, Folder 432)
- Salicaceae (Willow) Family. 1955-1961, Series 73.; 20 entries
  - Populus fremontii (Fremont's cottonwood).3/17/55 (Box 21, Folder 406)
  - Populus tremuloides (quaking aspen).5/1/55 (Box 21, Folder 407)
    Mammoth, Mono County, 7,500' elevation
  - Populus trichocarpa (black cottonwood).3/17/55 (Box 21, Folder 405)
  - Salix coulteri (Coulter willow).4/17/61 (Box 26, Folder 510)
    Dr. Tine Bridge, Smith River, Hwy #101, Del Norte County
  - Salix eastwoodiae (Eastwood's willow).8/20/56 (Box 20, Folder 395)
    moist meadow bordering Leevining Creek, Mono County, 1/2 mile above Ellery Lake, 9,450' elevation
  - Salix geyeriana var. argentea (Geyer willow).7/12/56 (Box 20, Folder 398)
    Wolverton Meadow, Sequoia National Park, 7,000' elevation
  - Salix gooddingii (black willow).2/24/59, 3/26/59 (Box 17, Folder 325)
  - Salix hindsiana (valley willow; sandbar willow).2/25/56 (Box 19, Folder 373)
    Tujunga Wash, Los Angeles County
  - Salix hookeriana (coast willow).3/28/56 (Box 20, Folder 399)
  - Salix jepsoni (Jepson willow).7/9/56, 7/24/56 (Box 21, Folder 401)
    female: Wolverton Meadow, Sequoia National Park, 7,000' elevation; male: Lassen National Park, 6,700' elevation
  - Salix laevigata var. araquipa (red willow).3/10/56, 5/27/56 (Box 20, Folder 388)
  - Salix lasiandra (yellow willow).7/9/56 (Box 20, Folder 385)
    Halstead Meadow, Sequoia National Park, 6,000' elevation
  - Salix lasiolepis (arroyo willow).2/20/56, 5/27/56 (Box 20, Folder 387)
    Oxnard, West 5th Street near ocean, Ventura County; Malibu and Mulholland Drive, Los Angeles County
  - Salix lemmonii (Lemmon's willow).7/9/56 (Box 20, Folder 393)
  - Salix monica (Mono willow).7/27/56 (Box 20, Folder 391)
    Glacier Canyon, east of Mt. Dana, Mono County, 10,550' elevation
  - Salix myrtillifolia (firm-leaf willow).7/11/56 (Box 20, Folder 397)
    male: south end of Crescent Meadow, Sequoia National Park, 7,240' elevation; female: along Bow River, Calgary, Canada, 3,400' elevation
  - Salix orestera (Sierra willow).8/20/56 (Box 20, Folder 396)
    moist borders of Tioga Lake, head of Leevining Canyon, Mono County, 9,600' elevation
  - Salix parksiana (Parks willow).4/17/61 (Box 26, Folder 511)
    Dr. Tine Bridge, Smith River, Hwy. #101, Del Norte County
  - Salix petrophila var. caespitosa (alpine willow).7/19/56 (Box 20, Folder 392)
    shores of Gradisky Lake, Tioga Crest, Mono County, 10,650' elevation
  - Salix scouleriana (Scouler willow).7/19/56 (Box 20, Folder 394)
    Shadley's Meadow behind service station, Grant Grove, 6,589' elevation
- Sapindaceae (Buckeye) Family. 1958, Series 74.; 1 entry
  one entry has been moved to Family: Hippocastanaceae, according to IPNI classification
  - Staphylea bolanderi (California bladdernut).3/29/58, 5/24/58 (Box 18, Folder 354)
- Sarraceniaceae (Pitcher-plant) Family., Series 75.; 1 entry
  - Darlingtonia californica (California pitcher plant; calf's head). (Box 14, Folder 280)
    no collection date; Plumas, Shasta, Siskiyou, Del Norte Counties; Oregon coast ranges; mostly meadow and along streams, 3,000'-6,000' elevation
- Saururaceae (Lizard's-tail) Family. 1951, Series 76.; 1 entry
  - Anemopsis californica (yerba mansa).8/31/51 (Box 15, Folder 281)
- Saxifragaceae (Saxifrage) Family. 1952-1959, Series 77.; 5 entries
  one entry has been moved to Family: Grossulariaceae, according to IPNI classification
  - Carpenteria californica (carpenteria).3/26/55 (Box 21, Folder 409)
  - Heuchera maxima (island heuchera).3/17/59 (Box 17, Folder 326)
  - Ribes aureum (golden currant).2/25/56 (Box 20, Folder 400)
  - Ribes malvaceum (chaparral flowering currant).2/20/52 (Box 15, Folder 282)
    also slide #230; Hidden Valley, Los Angeles County
  - Ribes speciosum (fuchsia-flowered gooseberry).2/3/52, 3/8/52 (Box 15, Folder 283)
- Scrophulariaceae (Figwort) Family. 1941-1961, Series 78.; 23 entries
  - Antirrhinum coulterianum (Coulter's snapdragon).5/14/43 (Box 15, Folder 284)
  - Antirrhinum glandulosum (viscid snapdragon).5/14/43 (Box 15, Folder 285)
  - Castilleja affinis var. linariaefolia (scarlet cup). (Box 15, Folder 286)
    no collection date; Sierra Nevada from Modoc to Kern Counties; south to Los Angeles County; montane, 4,000'-8,500' (fr. Jepson); plate uses genus: Castilleia
  - Castilleja angustifolia (paintbrush).3/16/41 (Box 15, Folder 287)
    Mint Canyon, Los Angeles County
  - Castilleja foliolosa (paintbrush).3/2/41 (Box 15, Folder 288)
  - Castilleja latifolia (seaside painted cup). (Box 15, Folder 289)
    no collection date; Monterey to Mendocino Counties; sea cliffs and rocky headlands along the coast, 10,500' elevation
  - Castilleja parviflora var. douglasii (indian paint brush).6/28/41 (Box 15, Folder 290)
    Big Bear Valley, San Bernardino County; plate uses genus: Castilleia
  - Diplacus puniceus (brick-red monkey-flower).7/17/42 (Box 15, Folder 291)
  - Galvesia speciosa (island snapdragon).4/3/54 (Box 15, Folder 292)
  - Mimulus bigelovii (monkey flower).3/20/41 (Box 15, Folder 293)
  - Mimulus cardinalis (scarlet moneky flower).7/3/41 (Box 15, Folder 294)
  - Mimulus guttatus (common monkey flower).6/11/41 (Box 15, Folder 295)
  - Mimulus longiflorus (bush monkey flower).4/15/60 (Box 23, Folder 458)
  - Orthocarpus purpurascens (owls-clover; escobita).5/15/42 (Box 15, Folder 296)
  - Pentstemon [Penstemon] antirrhinoides (snapdragon; pentstemon).5/23/55 (Box 21, Folder 414)
  - Pentstemon cordifolius (beard-tongue).7/3/41 (Box 15, Folder 297)
  - Pentstemon grinnellii (Grinnell pentstemon).6/3/52 (Box 15, Folder 298)
  - Pentstemon heterophyllus (violet beard-tongue). (Box 15, Folder 299)
    no collection date; Sierra Nevada foothills from Amador to Mariposa Counties; coast ranges from Mendocino south to San Diego Counties; 200'-5,500' elevation, May-June (fr. Jepson)
  - Pentstemon heterophyllus (foothill pentstemon).6/8/61 (Box 19, Folder 375)
  - Pentstemon labrosus (beard-tongue).7/16/41 (Box 15, Folder 300)
    Angeles National Forest
  - Pentstemon newberryi (mountain pride).6/1/42 (Box 16, Folder 301)
    Yosemite National Park, 4,000' elevation
  - Pentstemon spectabilis (magnificent pentstemon).5/10/42 (Box 16, Folder 302)
  - Pentstemon ternatus (beard-tongue).7/16/41 (Box 16, Folder 303)
- Solanaceae (Potato [Nightshade]) Family. 1942-1961, Series 79.; 7 entries
  - Datura meteloides (tolguacha). (Box 16, Folder 304)
    no collection date; Sacramento and San Joaquin Valleys to coastal So. California; Inyo County; Colorado Desert; sandy valley lands, 10'-4,000' elevation, July-Sept. (fr. Jepson)
  - Lycium brevipes (desert thorn; frutilla).5/3/58 (Box 18, Folder 353)
    Yaqui Well, Anza Borrego Desert, San Diego County
  - Lycium fremontii (Fremont thornbush).4/11/60 (Box 23, Folder 442)
    Salton Sea State Park
  - Nicotiana glauca (tree tobacco).9/25/55 (Box 19, Folder 372)
    Malibu, Los Angeles County
  - Physalis crassifolia (thick-leaved ground-cherry).4/22/61 (Box 26, Folder 505)
  - Solanum douglasii (black nightshade).8/25/51 (Box 16, Folder 305)
  - Solanum xanti (purple nightshade).5/15/42 (Box 16, Folder 306)
- Staphyleaceae (Bladdernut )Family., Series 80.
  entry has been moved to Family: Sapindaceae, according to IPNI classification
    one entry has been moved to Family: Sapindaceae, according to IPNI classification
- Sterculiaceae (Cacao) Family. 1958, Series 81.; 2 entries
  - Fremontia californica (California fremontia; flannel bush).3/29/58, 6/9/58 (Box 18, Folder 355)
    also slide #231; Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden; common family name on plate: Sterculia family
  - Fremontia californica var. mexicana (California slippery elm). (Box 216, Folder 307)
- Styracaceae (Storax) Family. 1955, Series 82.; 1 entry
  - Styrax officinalis var. californica (California styrax).5/21/55 (Box 21, Folder 413)
    El Dorado County
- Taxaceae (Yew) Family. 1942, Series 83.; 2 entries
  - Taxus brevifolia (western yew).9/15/42 (Box 16, Folder 308)
    also slide #232; middle fork of Mokelumne Rivers, Calaveras County, Sect. 10, T. 6 N, R. 15 E
  - Torreya californica (California nutmeg).9/15/42 (Box 16, Folder 309)
    also slide #233; small gulch, Calaveras County, Sect. 12, T. 5 N, R 12 E
- Taxodiaceae [Conifera] (Redwood) Family. 1942, Series 84.; 2 entries
  - Sequoia gigantea (giant sequoia; big tree).12/1/42 (Box 16, Folder 310)
    also slide #234; Sierra Nevada, Calaveras County
  - Sequoia sempervirens (redwood).11/15/42 (Box 16, Folder 311)
    also slide #235; Arcata, Humboldt County
- Thymelaeaceae (Mezereum) Family. 1959, Series 85.; 1 entry
  - Dirca occidentalis (western leatherwood).2/5/59, 4/2/59 (Box 17, Folder 327)
    Oakland Hills, Contra Costa County
- Trilliaceae Family. 1943, Series 86.; 4 entries
  - Trillium ovatum (western wakerobin).3/30/43 (Box 10, Folder 194)
    Mendocino County; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
  - Trillium rivale (brook trillium).4/10/43 (Box 10, Folder 195)
    Josephine County, OR; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
  - Trillium sessile californicum (common trillium; wake robin).3/30/43 (Box 10, Folder 196)
  - Trillium sessile rubra (common trillium; wakerobin).3/30/43 (Box 10, Folder 197)
- Ulmaceae (Elm) Family. 1958, Series 87.; 1 entry
  - Celtis reticulata (western hackberry).3/17/58, 8/26/58 (Box 18, Folder 356)
    University Arboretum, Davis
- Viscaceae [Loranthaceae] (Christmas Mistletoe) Family. 1958, Series 88.; 3 entries